<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dev Blog | Giacomo Lawrance</title>
    <description>My dev blog!</description>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 13:32:15 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 13:32:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Save time with .bat files</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you often type in the same repetitive commands on your CMD, .bat files are a great way to speed up your workflow. Essentially, you can create a .bat file to quickly run a script. For a simple example, if I wanted to build a site with Jekyll, usually I would have to type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;set JEKYLL_ENV=production&lt;/code&gt; to set Jekyll to build for a production environment, then type out &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec jekyll build&lt;/code&gt; to build the site. However, with .bat files, I can simple run the file and it does it all automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue I faced is that I wanted to add the .bat name as a command that I could execute in any folder I wanted. Luckily, this is incredibly easy to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put all your .bat files into a folder. I put mine into a scripts folder under /documents for easy access.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Copy the address of the folder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search for environment variables in Windows search. Select the ‘Edit the system environment variables’.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the Window that pops up, hit the ‘Environment Variables’ button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You should see an option for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Path&lt;/code&gt; like below. Click on it, and then click ‘Edit’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/2019-02-19-cmd/pathloc.png&quot; alt=&quot;Path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click ‘New’ on the right side.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paste in your address of the folder that you copied in step 2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you are done! You can call your .bat files by typing their names into the CMD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/2019-02-19-cmd/batfiles.png&quot; alt=&quot;Path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use this a lot when working with this blog and a few other Jekyll sites. It lets me serve, and build them, in a second instead of having to type out the command.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019/02/cmd-everywhere/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019/02/cmd-everywhere/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Web</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting up .env files with PHP</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t have a whole lot of experience with PHP, only having made relatively simple contact forms. However, this changed when I needed to make a HTML form that saved to a MySQL database. Setting up the form was easy enough, however I needed a way to hide the login details for the server in the PHP script that was launched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, it took me a lot of time to figure out how to use the .env file with PHP. I don’t have much experience with .env files, only having used it once or twice with Travis when testing Python applications dependent on APIs. For this reason, and my inexperience with PHP, it took me quite a while to figure out how to connect my .env file to my PHP script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, in my .env file I have the following. These are the details that allow the PHP script to connect to the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;SERVER=&quot;ser.ver.ip&quot;
USER=&quot;server_login_name&quot;
PASS=&quot;password&quot;
DBNAME=&quot;nameofdatabase&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to be able to set the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SERVER&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;USER&lt;/code&gt;, etc as a variable in PHP. To do this, I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://symfony.com/components/Dotenv&quot;&gt;Dotenv from symfony&lt;/a&gt;. Firstly, I had to install composer on my project by using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -s http://getcomposer.org/installer | php
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I needed to install Dotenv via composer into my project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;composer require --dev symfony/dotenv
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allowed me to load the dotenv files:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;use Symfony\Component\Dotenv\Dotenv;

$dotenv = new Dotenv();
$dotenv-&amp;gt;load(__DIR__.'/.env');
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, something I forgot to do was to enable the class auto loading mechanism that is provided by Composer. So, that goes on top of the dotenv loading code so it loads first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;require __DIR__ . '/vendor/autoload.php';
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This got the .env file linked to my PHP file, and let me declare my .env variables in PHP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$servername = getenv('SERVER');
$username = getenv('USER');
$password = getenv('PASS');
$dbname = getenv('DBNAME');
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could then refer to them in my code, in order to login into the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$conn = new mysqli($servername, $username, $password, $dbname);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a while to figure this out. I thought that PHP would automatically link the two files, but that clearly wasn’t true. Luckily, dotenv provided a quick and easy solution to the issue. I also wanted to secure .env and prevent people from being able to open it. Therefore, I went into .htaccess, and prevented people from looking at .htaccess and .env.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Deny access to .htaccess
&amp;lt;Files .htaccess&amp;gt;
    Order allow,deny
    Deny from all
&amp;lt;/Files&amp;gt;

# Deny access to .env
&amp;lt;Files .env&amp;gt;
	Order allow,deny
	Deny from all
&amp;lt;/Files&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this would lead the user to see a 403 page, I added a custom one in order to increase user retention, and to make the site look neater. I keep all my error pages in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/errordocs&lt;/code&gt;, as I have a few others for things like 404.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ErrorDocument 403 /errordocs/403.html
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also decided to disable the ability to get a directory listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Disable directory browsing
Options -Indexes
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all made sure that people couldn’t pry at the .env files and gain access to the server. I also made sure that the form itself was not vulnerable to SQL injections, and I did this by not directly using the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;INSERT&lt;/code&gt; statement. I also made sure that users could not put in semi colons or anything that would not be contained in a name.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019/02/env-php/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019/02/env-php/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Web</category>
        
        <category>php</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I Chose Jekyll For My Second Review Site</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had an increasing interest in anime and manga, and to have a little fun I decided to set up a second site to review this on. At first, I was going to use Wordpress, but after trying to set up add on domains, I just gave up. Besides, I wanted something light and simple, so Wordpress would defiantly not come to mind in that. I also didn’t want the stress of a second Wordpress site, so I decided to use Jekyll and GitHub pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The URL I settled with was &lt;a href=&quot;https://takanodan.net&quot;&gt;takanodan.net&lt;/a&gt;. This means &lt;em&gt;Band of the Hawk&lt;/em&gt;, which comes from my favourite manga and anime &lt;em&gt;Berserk&lt;/em&gt;. Plus, I think that the name sounds good, and the domain was £10 on Namecheap which is the domain registrar I use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may realize that this blog is also hosted on Jekyll. I haven’t had to maintain it and it’s been working great, and the theme is powerful and often updated. It allows me to keep SEO in mind, whilst still easily edit posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, to find a theme. I settled with the free &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wowthemesnet/mediumish-theme-jekyll&quot;&gt;Mediumish&lt;/a&gt; theme. I wanted a free theme as I didn’t want to spend too much on the second site, however I wanted something that looked professional and that worked well on GitHub pages. I needed something that would be able to cope with tons of review posts, and something which would allow the user to sort and search the reviews. Luckily, Mediumish allows you to do that. The search feature also works great, so when I finally start adding more reviews users can search the posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason I like Mediumish is that I can insert my custom CSS easily, and then use that in my own posts with HTML. For example, I give star reviews for each review, and I can simply insert my code and it shows up great. I use the following HTML:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star checked&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star checked&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;scss&lt;/code&gt; file, I added:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.checked {
	color: orange;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows me to easily give stars at the bottom of a post. For example, in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://takanodan.net/slime-review/&quot;&gt;Slime review on the site&lt;/a&gt;, I use the stars to give it a rating at the bottom of the page. I think it looks clean, and doesn’t affect site performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GiacomoLaw/blog/master/images/stars.png&quot; alt=&quot;Star rating&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I really like Jekyll and GitHub pages. It’s free, and runs really quickly. In addition, the developer of the theme I am using is very responsive to issues and questions, and the theme is maintained and new features are added which is really nice. The only thing that I have an issue with is caching, and I can’t figure a way out to clear the cache. But I don’t plan to update it that frequently so it shouldn’t be too much of an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is great for people who don’t want to spend hours sorting out site speed, issues with plugins, and so much more that Wordpress comes with. I had to do this for &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenerdystudent.com&quot;&gt;The Nerdy Student&lt;/a&gt;, and it wasn’t fun. I have to keep an eye on the site for issues, which is a pain too. But with Jekyll and &lt;a href=&quot;https://takanodan.net&quot;&gt;Taka No Dan&lt;/a&gt;, I have no issues. The site is fast, lightweight and easy to maintain. Perfect for a side project I don’t want to spend time on optimizing, but writing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019/02/why-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019/02/why-jekyll/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Web</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Torrenting on iOS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;iOS is an interesting platform when it comes to torrenting - previously, various apps were avaiable on the App Store, and they were soon removed. However, there are still ways to torrent on iOS, with the use on online torrent clients. Seedr is the best, free, online torrenting client that I’ve found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a note before I begin - many people believe that torrents are illegal, however that’s not true at all. Sites like HumbleBundle allow you to download large files via torrent, as it’s a much more reliable way to download files without them getting interrupted by network changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://seedr.cc&quot;&gt;Seedr&lt;/a&gt; allows you to paste your magnet link into the toolbox, and then simply hit enter to start downloading. It’s all automated, and requires no use of torrents at all. With the free plan, you can have up to 2 GB of torrents in your account at one time - this is great, as you can simply download one torrent, and then delete it. This is also backed by the fact that Seedr has unlimited bandwith, however you can only run a torrent for two hours on the free plan before it is stopped, which is a small disadvantage of the tool. Luckily, most 720/1080p torrents are small enough to fit inside the 2 GB offered for free, and usually do not take over 2 hours to download.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If 2 GB isn’t enough space for you, you can always share it on Twitter, YouTube, and other methods to get you up to 5 GB of space for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seedr is a great online torrent client, and the best that I’ve found so far to date. It also has premium plans that allow you to download torrents at the same time as others, and offers a lot more space. Premium plans also allow you to use different servers in order to increase the speed of downloads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then use &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenerdystudent.com/2017/03/icab-mobile-a-powerful-web-browser-for-ios/&quot;&gt;iCab&lt;/a&gt; to download the finished file, and watch it in &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/infuse-pro-5/id1136220915?mt=8&quot;&gt;Infuse 5 on my iPad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seedr can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seedr.cc/?r=1461626&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2018/09/Torrents-On-iOS/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2018/09/Torrents-On-iOS/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Other</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recovering Corrupt .FIT Files from Garmin Edge Devices</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago my Garmin Edge 810 froze, whcih meant I had to force shut it down whilst it was still recording a ride. Luckily, the files had been saved to the Garmins memory so I could access them through my PC, and pull them out. However, when I tried to upload it to Strava, it threw up an error that the files were corrupted, which I expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After searching around a little, I found this site: https://www.fitfiletools.com/#/top that allowed me to upload my FIT file, and fix it. I used the Corrupt Time Fixer, and this solved the corrupted file and meant that it could be uploaded to Strava and Garmin Connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully no one will be unlucky enough to encounter this issue, however if you do the website should be able to sort it out for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2018/09/Recovering-Corrupt-.FIT-Files-from-Garmin-Edge-Devices/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2018/09/Recovering-Corrupt-.FIT-Files-from-Garmin-Edge-Devices/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Other</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Formatting Code Snippets on Google Blogger</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of people use Blogger to host their blogs, but little know that you can actually edit the CSS that Blogger displays. It’s one of the most powerful Blogger features, and lets you truly customize your blog. You can get rid of elements you don’t like, change the look of content in your posts, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often have snippets of code on my large blog, &lt;a href=&quot;thenerdystudent.com&quot;&gt;The Nerdy Student&lt;/a&gt;, however Blogger never actually formatted those pieces of code. I had to go into the HTML editor, and add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to every piece of code, however that only changed the font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that the CSS editor may allow me to change this - and to my suprise, it did! I knew you could edit the look of the site with it, but I didn’t know you could edit the look of the post content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GiacomoLaw/blog/raw/master/images/1.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Click the customize button in the Theme tab&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You then scroll down to the advanced section, and click ‘Edit CSS’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GiacomoLaw/blog/raw/master/images/editingcss.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Hit Advanced, scroll down, and then select CSS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to use the Bootstrap style code for my blog - I had used it on many websites before, and I loved the way it looked. I entered this in the box below pre-existing CSS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;code {
  font-family: monospace, monospace;
  font-size: 1em;
    padding: 0.2rem 0.4rem;
  font-size: 90%;
  color: #bd4147;
  background-color: #f7f7f9;
  border-radius: 0.25rem;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And done! I hit save, and now my code snippets on my blog look nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GiacomoLaw/blog/raw/master/images/html_on_blog.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;The code snippets as seen in my [Bear Notes](http://www.thenerdystudent.com/2017/02/bear-notes-write-beautifully-on-iphone.html) review&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2017/04/Formatting-Code-Snippets-On-Blogger/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2017/04/Formatting-Code-Snippets-On-Blogger/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Web</category>
        
        <category>html</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting up a HTML Email Signature</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I use email a lot when, probably more than any other form of contact or social media. I decided to make a HTML email signature for myself, but found that I couldn’t put the raw code into the email, and have the email render it into a signature. However, there is an easy way to get around this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GiacomoLaw/blog/raw/master/images/FullSizeRender.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My personal email signature&quot; title=&quot;My personal email signature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can make a HTML signature as complex or as simple as you want, and there is so much flexibility in making one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my source code for my blog signature:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; &amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tbody&amp;gt;&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;td style=&quot;padding-bottom: 5px;&quot;&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;tbody&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;td style=&quot;padding-bottom: 5px;&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;http://thenerdystudent.com&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img data-class=&quot;external&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/GiacomoLaw/TNS-images/raw/master/AN%20header.png&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; alt=&quot;The Nerdy Student&quot; style=&quot;display: block&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; --&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;td style=&quot;padding-bottom: 5px; font-family: Arial; font-size: 12pt; color: rgb(51, 51, 51);&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font style=&quot;color: #333333; font-size: 12pt; font-family: Arial&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Giacomo Lawrance&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
                
                &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;td style=&quot;font-family: Arial; font-size: 10pt;&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font style=&quot;color: #333333; font-size: 10pt; font-family: Arial&quot;&amp;gt;Email:&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenerdystudent@gmail.com&quot; style=&quot;color: #06c&quot;&amp;gt;thenerdystudent@gmail.com&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;td style=&quot;font-family: Arial; font-size: 10pt;&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font style=&quot;color: #333333; font-size: 10pt; font-family: Arial&quot;&amp;gt;Blog:&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;http://thenerdystudent.com&quot; style=&quot;color: #06c&quot;&amp;gt;thenerdystudent.com&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;td style=&quot;font-family: Arial; font-size: 10pt;&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font style=&quot;color: #333333; font-size: 10pt; font-family: Arial&quot;&amp;gt;Website:&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;http://giacomolaw.me&quot; style=&quot;color: #06c&quot;&amp;gt;giacomolaw.me&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;/tbody&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;bottom&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 5px; vertical-align: bottom;&quot;&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;tbody&amp;gt;&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
                    
                    &amp;lt;td style=&quot;padding-left: 5px;&quot;&amp;gt;
                        &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/GiacomoLaw&quot;&amp;gt;
                            
                        &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
                    
                    
                &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;/tbody&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;tbody&amp;gt;&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;td style=&quot;padding-bottom: 5px; padding-top: 5px;&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;http://thenerdystudent.com&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img data-class=&quot;external&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/GiacomoLaw/TNS-images/raw/master/Header.png&quot; width=&quot;420px&quot; alt=&quot;The Nerdy Student&quot; style=&quot;display: block&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
                
                &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GiacomoLaw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GiacomoLaw/giacomolaw.github.io/raw/master/img/twitter.png&quot; width=&quot;40px&quot; alt=&quot;Twitter&quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;
&amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GiacomoLaw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GiacomoLaw/giacomolaw.github.io/raw/master/img/Github.png&quot; width=&quot;40px&quot; alt=&quot;Github&quot;/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; 
&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;/tbody&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/tbody&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s quite long, but it does look good:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/GiacomoLaw/blog/raw/master/images/IMG_8713.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Blog email signature&quot; title=&quot;My blog email signature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After storing my signature code into a GitHub repo, I found a very useful site that allows you to edit HTML, and see the results in real time. You can find it &lt;a href=&quot;http://htmledit.squarefree.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty simple to get the resulting HTLM into the email signature - just highlight the preview and copy and paste it into your email app. In Gmail, you can just paste it straight into the signature box, and if you use &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/spark-love-your-email-again/id997102246?mt=8&quot;&gt;Spark for iPad and iPhone&lt;/a&gt;, you can select HTML and paste it in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it! Now you have a lovely looking HTML signature. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you are unsure where to start, you could always find a email signature you like, and use that source code. Or, you could use a signature maker and use that source code, and then work of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this helped!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2017/04/Setting-Up-a-HTML-Email-Signature/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2017/04/Setting-Up-a-HTML-Email-Signature/</guid>
        
        
        <category>html</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all! I have decided to set up a smaller blog alongside &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenerdystudent.com&quot;&gt;The Nerdy Student&lt;/a&gt; for unrelated things and things about programming! It won’t have a schedule, and will be updated every once in a while when I want to post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll post intresting things I come across, challenges whilst programming, and other things I feel like posting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2017/04/Welcome!/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2017/04/Welcome!/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Other</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
